W.A.C. Bennett fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Photographs, 1915 - 1981; F-55-58; 1723 photographs (prints; black and white and colour) 17 photographic contact sheets (black and white) 15 photographic negatives (black and white and colour) 5 slides (colour); Predominant dates are 1950-1970. The dates of the portraits of Bennett's family and fr
  - Premier of British Columbia, 1941 - 1981; F-55-58-2; 1227 photographs: prints; black and white and colour 8 photographs: contact sheets 8 photographs: negatives; black and white
    - Ceremonial activities, 1952 - 1981; F-55-58-2-2; 1057 photographs: prints; black and white and colour 5 photographs: contact sheets; Photographs from Bennett's visits to Hong Kong and Japan are held in three adhesive albums. Photographs from L'ecu de France dinner were held in individual red f
      Sub-subseries consists of photographs arising from Bennett's ceremonial activities as Premier, such as official openings and dedications, official visits and tours, and government social gatherings. Photos of official visits and tours relate to Bennett's trips to Europe, Hong Kong, Japan, and locations in Canada. Photos of opening ceremonies relate to the opening of the Pacific Great Eastern Railway, the Arrow Dam, the COMINCO research centre, the Fraser Wharves, the Interprovincial Steel and Pipe Co. Ltd. plant, the Malahat Highway, the Nine Mile Canyon Bridge, and other projects. Photos of government social gatherings relate to the Pacific Coast Curling Association dinner, B.C. Sports Hall of Fame presentations, and other events.
      See Appendix B for an item-level description of each photograph included in file F-55-58-2-2-31.
      - B.C. Sports Hall of Fame presentations, 1971 - 1981; F-55-58-2-2-1 (Archival box - standard 55-106)
        Photographic materials
      - Interprovincial Steel and Pipe Co. Ltd. plant opening, 1955 - 1977; F-55-58-2-2-2 (Archival box - standard 55-106, Archival box - small 55-117)
      - Miscellaneous openings, dedications, and visits, 1955 - 1974; F-55-58-2-2-3 (Archival box - standard 55-106, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Fraser Wharves facilities opening on Jul. 25, 1972, F-55-58-2-2-4 (Archival box - standard 55-106)
      - L'ecu de France dinner in London, England on Oct. 5, 1971, F-55-58-2-2-5 (Archival box - standard 55-89)
      - Hong Kong visit, 1970; F-55-58-2-2-6 (Archival box - standard 55-89)
      - Expo '70 (Osaka, Japan) visit, 1970; F-55-58-2-2-7 (Archival box - standard 55-89)
      - Osaka, Kyoto, and Tokyo, Japan visit, 1970; F-55-58-2-2-8 (Archival box - standard 55-115)
      - Finland and Belgium visits, 1975; F-55-58-2-2-9 (Archival box - standard 55-107)
      - Unidentified visit, 1975; F-55-58-2-2-10 (Archival box - standard 55-107)
      - Quebec visit, 1969; F-55-58-2-2-11 (Archival box - standard 55-107)
      - Arrow Dam dedication, 1969; F-55-58-2-2-12 (Archival box - standard 55-107)
      - Miscellaneous visits [Europe], 1968 - 1969; F-55-58-2-2-13 (Archival box - standard 55-107)
      - Mrs. L.D. Nayar visit to Victoria, 1968; F-55-58-2-2-14 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Presentation of Pacific Great Eastern Railway car No. 2 to the City of Squamish, 1967; F-55-58-2-2-15 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Bavarian foreign minister meeting from Jun. 12-16, 1967, F-55-58-2-2-16 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Krauss-Maffei (Munich, Germany) visit on Oct. 5, 1966, F-55-58-2-2-17 (Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Columbia Treaty Project (Arrow Dam) official ceremonies, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-18 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Arrow Dam construction commencement ceremonies, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-19 (Archival box - standard 55-108, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - London, England (Reed Paper Group) visit, 1964; F-55-58-2-2-20 (Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Pacific Coast Curling Association dinner on Feb. 7, 1962, F-55-58-2-2-21 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Major-General Vanier and Madame Vanier visit to B.C., 1960; F-55-58-2-2-22 (Artifact box - large 55-96)
      - Austria meeting, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-23 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Metal manufacturing plant tour, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-24 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Paris visit, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-25 (Archival box - standard 55-115)
      - [Manuel Fraga Iribarne, Spanish Minister of Information and Tourism] meeting, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-26 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Farmers' meeting with Bennett, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-27 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Celebration of the elimination of British Columbia's debt, 1959; F-55-58-2-2-28 (Archival box - standard 55-108)
      - Consolidated Mining and Smelting Company of Canada Limited (COMINCO) research opening, 1957; F-55-58-2-2-29 (Archival box - standard 55-109)
      - Pacific Great Eastern Railway inaugural run, 1956; F-55-58-2-2-30 (Archival box - standard 55-109)
      - Miscellaneous functions, activities as Premier, 1952 - 1954; F-55-58-2-2-31; File contains the following photographic items: – W.A.C. Bennett lifted by two supporters after his elections as leader of the Social Credit Party of B.C. (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett as Premier two days before officially taking office (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett seated as his desk at first day of work as Premier (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and first Social Credit cabinet at swearing-in ceremony on August 1 (1952) – Mort Ferguson, Hon. Tilly Rolston, W.A.C. Bennett, and Mrs. Bennett at the opening of the P.N.E. (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett, Mrs. Bennett, and the Mayor of Rochester, England on the reviewing stand of the P.N.E. Parade (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and two girls at the opening of the Social Credit picnic in Victoria, B.C. (1952) – Governor-General Vincent Massey, receiving the public at the Legislative Assembly in Victoria (1952) – Solon E. Low, M.P., W.A.C. Bennett, and Hon. Lyle Wicks, Minister of Labour, at Victoria, B.C. (1952) – Mr. and Mrs. R.B. Worley and Mr. and Mrs. Bennett at the opening night of the York Theatre in Victoria (1952) – Governor-general Vincent Massey with W.A.C. Bennett and Mrs. Bennett at the C.P.R. docks in Victoria (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett, R.B. Worley, Einar Gunderson, and others at the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett with two individuals holding a bent railway spike at the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – Einar Gunderson, J.A. Kennedy, W.A.C. Bennett, John Hart and Jim Stewart holding a spike at the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – Front of engine car for the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett, Einar Gunderson, and unidentified individual in dining car of P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – Einar Gunderson, W.A.C. Bennett. and other individuals being presented with a bouquet by a young girl in Quesnel at the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – P.G.E. railway cars crossing a bridge (1952) – Einar Gunderson, W.A.C. Bennett, Jim Stewart, J.A. Kennedy, and other individuals in front of open car of P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – P.G.E. railway cars running along the side of a hill (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and entourage in open car of P.G.E. extenstion to Prince George, with reporters and spectators looking on (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett giving a speech from the open car of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – Individual with hammers and railway spike at the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett giving a speech at the railway platform of Prince George (1952) – Unidentified individual giving a speech at the railway platform of Prince George, with W.A.C. Bennett, Einar Gunderson, and other individuals looking on (1952) – Parade in unidentified city for the arrival of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – Group of spectators and reports at event for the opening of the P.G.E. extenstion to Prince George (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett at Britannia Beach for the opening of the P.G.E. extension to Prince George (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett with telegrams one day after elections of M.L.A.'s Bonner and Gunderson in by-elections (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett, Einar Gunderson, R.B.Worley, and other Individuals at Premier’s Conference in Edmonton, Alberta (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and unidentified individual [Premier Manning?] at Premier’s Conference in Edmonton, Alberta (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and unidentified individual [Premier Manning?] at Premier’s Conference in Edmonton, Alberta (1952) – W.A.C. Bennett and unidentified individual [Premier Manning?] at Premier’s Conference in Edmonton, Alberta (1952) – Opening of Legislative Assembly (1953) – Arrival of Lieutenant-Governor for the opening of the Legislative Assembly (1953) – Procession of Lieutenant-Governor for the opening of the opening of the Legislative Assembly (1953) – Harold Winch, W.A.C. Bennett, and Carl Goldenberg at a government reception (2 prints) (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett, Tilly Rolston, and R.B. Worley and other individuals at a ball (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett, Mrs. Bennett, and other individuals at a ball (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett, Mrs. Bennett [and R.J. Bennett and Bill Bennett] at a ball (1953) – Mr. and Mrs. W.A.C. Bennett, and Mr. and Mrs. R.B. Worley at a ball (1953) – Tilly Rolston, W.A.C. Bennett, and other individuals at a banquet (1953) – Mr. and Mrs. Bennett, Tilly Rolston, and other individuals at a reception (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett and others at a reception (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett and supporters after a meeting in New Westminster (1953) – W.A.C. Bennett giving a speech at a meeting in New Westminster (1953) – Einar Gunderson, W.A.C. Bennett, R.B. Worley, and [Robert Bonner] boarding train to Ottawa (1953) – Mr. and Mrs. W.A.C. Bennett, and Helen on board the S.S. Durango (1954) – Speaker of the Legislative Assembly and the Sergeant at Arms (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett leaving New Westminster for a holiday (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett seated at his desk (1954) – Opening of Legislative Assembly (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett shaking hands with the Lieutenant-Governor of B.C. on the front steps of the Legislative building in Victoria (1954) – Bob Sommers, Wes Black, W.A.C. Bennett, Dave Armstrong, and Ron Worley on a boat to Chatham Island (1954) – Bob Sommers, Ron Worley, W.A.C. Bennett, Wes Black, and Dave Armstron on a boat to Chatham Island (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett disembarking from boat to Chatham Island (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett, Ron Worley, Wes Black, Bob Sommers, and an unidentified individual walking down a ramp to boat docks (1954) – Dave Armstrong, W.A.C. Bennett, Ron Worley, and other individuals at building site for CKDA transmitter towers (1954) – Dave Armstrong, Wes Black, W.A.C. Bennett, Bob Sommers, Ron Worley, and other individuals looking up at CKDA transmitters (1954) – W.A.C. Bennett switching on CKDA’s new power increase (1954) (Archival box - standard 55-109)
      - Lieutenant Governor of BC visit to Victoria, 1953; F-55-58-2-2-32 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Malahat Highway opening, 1955; F-55-58-2-2-33 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Nine Mile Canyon Bridge opening, 1955; F-55-58-2-2-34 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Unidentified highway opening, 1955; F-55-58-2-2-35 (Archival box - standard 55-110, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Pacific Great Eastern Railway Peace River special inaugural run, 1955; F-55-58-2-2-36 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Royal Family visits, 1959 - 1971; F-55-58-2-2-37 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Miscellaneous functions and activities as Premier, vol. 1, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-38 (Archival box - standard 55-110)
      - Miscellaneous functions and activities as Premier, vol. 2, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-39 (Archival box - standard 55-111)
      - Miscellaneous functions and activities as Premier, vol. 3, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-40 (Archival box - standard 55-111, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Miscellaneous functions and activities as Premier, vol. 4, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-41 (Archival box - standard 55-111, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Miscellaneous functions and activities as Premier, vol. 5, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-42 (Archival box - standard 55-111, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - May Bennett at events, 1952 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-43 (Archival box - standard 55-111, Shelf Map cabinet)
      - Phillips Cables, Vancouver plant opening, 1957; F-55-58-2-2-44 (Archival box - standard 55-111)
      - Nancy Greene with Bennett, 1968; F-55-58-2-2-45 (Archival box - standard 55-111)
      - Hotel Vancouver dinner, 1971; F-55-58-2-2-46 (Archival box - standard 55-111)
      - University events, 1965; F-55-58-2-2-47 (Archival box - standard 55-111)
      - Promotional Bennett photos (oversize), 1965 - 1979; F-55-58-2-2-48 (Artifact box - large 55-96)
    - British Columbia government projects, 1941 - 1965; F-55-58-2-3; 196 photographs: prints; black and white and colour; Peace River project photographs are laminated. Photographs of brush cutting activities are glued onto sheets of paper.
      Sub-subseries consists of photographs arising from various construction projects and other undertakings of the British Columbia government. Materials relate to the Okanagan Lake Bridge, the Trail Bridge, the Port Mann Bridge, the Deas Island Tunnel, the Castlegar pulp mill, the British Columbia Vocational School, the Peace River project, various B.C. Power Commission projects, brush cutting activities in various areas of B.C., and other projects.
      - Peace River project, 1959 - 1964; F-55-58-2-3-1 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - B.C. Power Commission projects, 1956 - 1962; F-55-58-2-3-2 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - Trail Bridge construction, 1961; F-55-58-2-3-3 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - Castlegar pulp mill construction, 1961; F-55-58-2-3-4 (Archival box - standard 55-112, Archival box - small 55-117)
      - Port Mann Bridge project, 1965; F-55-58-2-3-5 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - Deas Island Tunnel construction, 1965; F-55-58-2-3-6 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - British Columbia Vocational School in Burnaby and Namaimo, B.C., 1965; F-55-58-2-3-7 (Archival box - standard 55-112)
      - Automotive and heavy duty welding building, 1965; F-55-58-2-3-8 (Archival box - standard 55-113)
      - Okanagan Lake Bridge construction, 1957 - 1958; F-55-58-2-3-9 (Archival box - standard 55-113)
      - Brush-cutting activities, 1941; F-55-58-2-3-10 (Archival box - standard 55-113, Archival box - small 55-117)
      - Port Mann Bridge project (oversize), 1965; F-55-58-2-3-11 (Artifact box - large 55-97)
    - Protests against government policies, 1965 - 1969; F-55-58-2-4; 14 photographs: prints; black and white 3 photographs: contact sheets; Photograph of Surrey NDP Service Centre is badly discoloured.
      Sub-subseries consists of photographs arising from protests held against various government policies. Sub-subseries includes photographs and contact sheets. Materials relate to a protest held by carpenters and ironworkers, and a protest by farmers against Bill 42. Photographs of the carpenters' and ironworkers' protest include a photograph of the Surrey NDP Service Centre, and photographs of protesters at a bus depot. Photographs of the farmers' protest show farmers protesting outside the Legislature in Victoria, and Bennett addressing some protesters in the crowd.
      - Carpenters and Ironworkers' protests, 1965; F-55-58-2-4-1 (Archival box - standard 55-113)
      - Farmers' protest against Bill 42, 1965; F-55-58-2-4-2 (Archival box - standard 55-113)
  - British Columbia Social Credit Party, 1955 - 1975; F-55-58-3; 130 photographs: prints; black and white and colour 7 photographs: negatives; colour 9 photographs: contact sheets
    Subseries consists of photographs arising from activities of the British Columbia Social Credit Party. Subseries includes photographs, negatives, and contact sheets. Materials relate to Social Credit elections, conventions, rallies, meetings, election night gatherings; and the retirement of W.A.C. Bennett. Election photographs include photos of an election parade and rally for the 1968 Social Credit candidate for North Vancouver. Subseries also includes a scrapbook compiled by the Primrose League to honour W.A.C. Bennett in his retirement. Scrapbook contains photographs of various Social Credit figures, as well as letters thanking Bennett for his years of service to British Columbia.
    - Conventions, rallies, meetings, and election night gatherings, 1955 - 1975; F-55-58-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 55-113, Archival box - standard 55-114, Shelf Map cabinet)
    - Bennett retirement scrapbook, 1973 - 1974; F-55-58-3-0-2 (Artifact box - large 55-97)
    - Social Credit parade and rally in North Vancouver on July 8, 1968, F-55-58-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 55-114)